ILGWU Local 23-25 Photographs 5780/059 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Local 23-25 Photographs
1986-2007
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Local 23-25
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/059 P
4.11 cubic feet
4.1 linear ft.
Photographs.
This collection primarily consists of photographs by Kathy Andrade and George Colon. Photographs document meetings, rallies, Labor Day parades, and other local union events.
6325271
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 08, 2011
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 10, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Locals 23 and 25 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), as well as the local resulting from their merger, local 23-25, also known as the Blouse, Skirt, and Sportswear Workers' Union, were based in New York, New York. Local 23 was chartered in 1903; Local 25 was chartered in 1905.
Scope and Contents
This collection primarily consists of photographs by Kathy Andrade and George Colon. Photographs document meetings, rallies, Labor Day parades, and other local union events.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/059: ILGWU Local 23-25 Records 5780/059 PUBS: ILGWU Local 23-25 Publications 5780/095: ILGWU Local 23-25 Records 5780/095 G: ILGWU Local 23-25 graphics 5780/042: ILGWU Local 25 Publication "L'Operaia" 5780/139 mf: ILGWU Local 25 Publication "L'Operaia" on Microfilm 5780/071: ILGWU Local 25 Publication "The Message"
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Women's clothing industry -- New York (State) -- New York; Labor unions -- Clothing workers -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing workers -- United States; Clothing workers -- New York (State) -- New York; Industrial relations -- United States; Industrial relations -- New York (State) -- New York; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 23-25 (New York, N.Y.)
6325271
- ILGWU. Local 23-25 - (Box 1)
  - Women Garment Workers (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    2 large format photographs
- Information about photos by Kathy Andrade and George Colon (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Photos by Kathy Andrade and George Colon, #11-20 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Includes: Jay Mazurs speaks with union members, Arthur Silverstein, Kathy Andrade, Cecila Cruz; Kathy Andrade et. al, recording secretary of panel, Seminar for Leadership Training at Rutgers; Zoila Neto, Miriam Ulloa (El Salvador); Local 23-25; Local 23-25 graduation ceremony receiving certificates, English class held in Chinatown, Mr Daniel Lam, teacher; Union meeting in a hotel, Ed Koch addresses the audience at the Roosevelt Hotel; Ida Torres (Cornell), Director of Local 1S [SEIU] addresses the class at Abraham and Strauss; anniversary, Triangle Fire, Berenson (Manager, Local 91), Andrade, Sophia Bueno, Education Director, Local 66; Members vote, chair ladies and Executive Board voting on contract; Hubert Humphrey speaks at 7th Avene Rally, Louis Stulberg shares dais; English class in Chinatown, Professor Daniel Lam, Transfiguration Parochial School; Chinese New Year Celebration at High School of Fashion Industries, a famous Chinese singer from Hong Kong in the 1970s
- Photos by Kathy Andrade and George Colon, #21-30 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Labor Day Parade, "ILGWU supports undocumented workers," Ms. Barzia from Cuba in front with her boyfriend; Labor Day Parade, Annette Leon with her boyfriend, 1976; Labor Day Parade, 1988, Chinese contingent, Katie Quan and Wai Chun Ng, Cindy Sai Leung, Yuk Ling Tang, Mary Chin, Yuk Lin Sun, Mei Yin Tsang, Lana Cheung and others; Labor Day Parage, Local 23-25, 1976; Labor Day Parade, Gloria Fuentes, Lucy Hernandez; Labor Day Parade with Celia Flores, 1976; Labor Day Parade, 1989, Chinese contingent, May Leung, Betty Lee (summer intern), Wai Chun Ng, Mary Chin, Lai Ying Chin; Labor Day Parade, Ju-el Manufacturing Company; Labor Day Parade, The ILGWU Chorus, Ms. Rivera in the wheel chair
- Photos by Kathy Andrade and George Colon, #31-40 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Includes: Joel Marte, Kathy Andrade and Sam Wong flanking the Chinese band in the background; Solidaridad signs with Chinese characters as well, celebrating Lech Walesa, Polish workers march; Pete Seeger with his guitar at a picnic on Labor Day; Labor Day Parade; Chinese English class with Jay Mazur; Concert at PS 124, Chinese Choral Group New Year celebration; Parade celebrating Lech Walesa; promoting the Union Label in the Labor Day Parade; parade celebrating newly naturalized and registered citizens; parade to roll back imports
- Photos by Kathy Andrade and George Colon, #41-60 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Includes: Dress manufacturers' employees march in the Labor Day Parade, Boat ride, Kathy Andrade with a presser and his two children; Ju-el Manufacturing
- ILGWU Local 23-25 (Box 3)
  - Chinese CLUW Activities and Other Photographs (Box 3)
    Includes: Chinese CLUW (Coalition of Labor Union Women) activities, 1986-1989; 4 posters with a total of 26 photographs, some captions in Chinese. Also includes Louis Stulberg portrait by Jerry Soalt and 3 portraits of workers, reproduced by Wayne State University Archives of Labor and Urban Affairs.
- [Rallies, trainings], 1964-1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Strike, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 3)
- [Mounted exhibit photographs] (Box 4, Folder 4)
- [Mounted exhibit photographs] (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Chinatown dress shops 4/85, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Slides
- Chinatown exterior shots 4/85, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Slides, April 1985
- Local 23-25 contract negotiations 4/2/85, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Slides, April 2, 1985
- ILGWU Health Center 4/85, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- ILGWU Health Center 4/85, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- ILGWU Health Center 4/85, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- ILGWU Health Center 4/85, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- ILGWU Health Center (and van driver Wilson) (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Labor Day 9/3/84, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Slides, September 3, 1984
- Local 23-25 general membership meetings 3/27/85, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Slides, March 27, 1985
- Local 23-25 general membership meeting 3/27/85, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Left overs film strip slides (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Naturalized citizens 11/14/86, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Slides, November 14, 1986
- Pre-retirement seminar-shops 11/18/86, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Slides, November 18, 1986
- Edgar Romney at Chinatown classes 11/25/86, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Slides, November 25, 1986
- 1982 ILGWU and strike pictures (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Still slides from "We Are One" 2/87, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  Slides, February 1987
- Still slides from "We Are One" 2/87, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Untitled slides (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Untitled slides (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Untitled slides (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Take Our Daughters To Work Day, 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Includes correspondence, and information about artist Jolanta Pienczykowski
- ILGWU Chinese CLUW 10th Anniversary Group, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Includes Shui Ying Yan, Ying Ya Tsai, Cindy Sai Leung, Betty Leung, Jenny Shig Jing Ng, Alice Ip, Edgar Romney, Katie Quan, Shui Mak Ka, Doris Kee, Shun Nan Young, Sau King Chew, Ying Fong Chan, Wai Chun Ng, Lana Cheung, Ching Hang Lee, Ying Yi Deng, Kuen Li, Yuk Lin Sun, Yook Chee Hom, Anita Sheung Ngor Leung, Miu Shun Chan, Kam Fan Li, May Chen, Agnes Wong, Connie Ling, Yim Un Chan, Mei Yung Liew, Lai Fong Leung, Chung Ng, Mei Yin Tsang
- Photos for Local 23-25's wall (and others) (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
  Includes: Kit Ling at sewing machine (La Del); labor day parade with banner; labor day parade with dancing women in front; 63-32 members in tee-shirts that say UNITE Against Sweatshops; retirees with No tax dollars for sweatshop uniforms signs; picketers in front of Profiles; woman pattern-making (Lad Del); woman with baby on back in 1982 strike; photo of baby's face in 1982 strike; Chinatown daycare kids with banner in labor day parade; APALA convention on August 20, 1993; cutter from unseen America photo class; King Ling supervising member in sewing room, Teddy Fung; Lin Tai sewing, Teddy Fung; woman packaging clothes in plastic (La Del); man at knitting machine, Local 155; woman at sewing machine, Local 155; men at pressing machines with steam, Local 155; hands at sewing machine; Chinese women in busy sewing factory from 1989; crowd of 1982 strike with signs We Are One!; crowd in 1982 strike with raised arms
- Lobbying for FMLA - L23-25 [Wai Chun Ng + Son Burton, Alice 1p (back) Susan Cowell] (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Asian Labor Festival & Other Conventions (1) (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Asian Labor Festival & Other Conventions (2) (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Asian Labor Festival & Other Conventions (3) (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Shop Photos - Mademoiselle Knitwear 1987/1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- ILGWU Solidarity Parade [NYC] Jan. 1988 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Women's Association Dinner 3/7/1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- May Chen NY Times/Alumnae Search Brochure Photograph 1990 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- APALA & Asian Labor Festival 1991 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- American Family Celebration [CLUW] 1988 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- ILGWU May Chen Presentations [Miscellaneous] 1994 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- HIC Parade 7/6/1997 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  negatives
- Classroom Photograph March 1998 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Extra Negatives (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Convention May Chen 1995 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Democratic Mayoral Candidates Debate 2005 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Office Activities 2002 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Children's School Presentation (Box 7, Folder 18)
- John Gillis Award (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Pre-Retirement Seminar 1994 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Activities 2002 (1) (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Activities 2002 (2) (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Activities [1] 2001 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Activities [2] 2001 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Activities [3] 2001 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Activities [4] 2001 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Activities [5] 2001 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- UNITE! Activities [Justice for James Yee, New American Democratic Club, Textbook Scholarship Ceremony] 2004 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- UNITE! Activities [Justice for James Yee, New American Democratic Club, Textbook Scholarship Ceremony] 2004 (2) (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Activities 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Misc. Photos 1989-2007 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Bridge Builders Awards - May Chen 2007 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Stop Sweatshops, Unity Team (Box 7, Folder 33)
- UNITE! Extra-Give Away 2003 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Wang Coalition of Labor Union Women 2005 (Box 7, Folder 35)
- X-Mas 2003 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Asian Labor Committee NYC Central Labor Council/AFL-CIO APALA Asian Pacific American Alliance May 1992 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- May Chen - Asian Americans for David Dinkins (Box 7, Folder 38)
- 100th Anniversary. Local 23-25 UNITE! Asian Labor Fair 1993-1995 (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Breast Cancer Walkathon (Box 7, Folder 40)
- Asian Labor Festival & Other Conventions (1) 1992 (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Asian Labor Festival & Other Conventions (2) 1992 (Box 7, Folder 42)
- UNITE HERE! Speech Conference (Box 8, Folder 1)
- UNITE HERE: Mei Young, Connie, Luisa 2007 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Labor Tour to China Aug. 14-19, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Immigrant Freedom Ride (Queens, Museum, Flushing Park) 2003 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- CLUW Party 2006 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- UNITE Parade 2003 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- CPC Dinner (Box 8, Folder 7)
- IUC Meeting in WDC 5/2005 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- MUC, Conference, Baton Rouge, LA (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Visitor from Viet Nam 2006 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Local 10 Party May 2007 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Immigration Project Staff, May Chen, Retirement Party Office Holiday Party 2001-2005 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- UNITE Here 74th Anniversary 2007 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous: NYC NAACP (1) (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous: NYC NAACP (2) (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous: NYC NAACP (3) (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Local 23-25 ILGWU Silver Palace Coalition of Labor Women 1994 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- NYC Central Labor Council March 1999 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- NYC Rally Immigrant Workers - Freedom Ride 10/4/2003 (1) (Box 8, Folder 19)
- NYC Rally Immigrant Workers - Freedom Ride 10/4/2003 (2) (Box 8, Folder 20)
- International Labor Meeting: Sweden June 2000 (1) (Box 8, Folder 21)
- International Labor Meeting: Sweden June 2000 (2) (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Misc. Photos (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Misc. Photos (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Chinese New Year (Box 9)
  - Chinese New Year (Box 9)
    removed from box 7
- Chinese New Year Party 2/9/2005 (Box 10)
  - Chinese New Year Party: 2/9/2005 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous: [to Walter from May Chen], 1995 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Photos, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- NYC - CLUM Luncheon: 10/23/1993 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Day Care Center Staff Photos (1 of 2), 1992 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Day Care Center Staff Photos (2 of 2), 1992 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- APALA Photos: Police, EMS Kali Silat, Human Rts., Carpenters DOL, Local 371 TWU (1 of 2), 1993-1996 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- APALA Photos: Police, EMS Kali Silat, Human Rts., Carpenters DOL, Local 371 TWU (2 of 2), 1993-1996 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- APALA Photos: Police, EMS Kali Silat, Human Rts., Carpenters DOL, Local 371 TWU (3 of 3), 1993-1996 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- APALA Photos, 2003-2005 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous: Connie's New Home, ESL Conference, Acupuncture Dinner, Labor Day Fall 1990-1991 (early) (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Activities (ESL), 1992 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Chinese CLUW Parties (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Roll B Photos: Includes Amy Li, Max Tjong, Ms. Jia, Mr. Goldstein, Mr. Crossa, Mr. Wou, Mr. Blonstein, Chuck Lee, Bob Jones (1 of 2) June 1989 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Roll B Photos: Includes Amy Li, Max Tjong, Ms. Jia, Mr. Goldstein, Mr. Crossa, Mr. Wou, Mr. Blonstein, Chuck Lee, Bob Jones (2 of 2) June 1989 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Photos include: S. Lew, Eula Moy, Joe Lam, Qiv, Sybil Wong, Wu, Paul Wing, Shien, Leung-Tokar, Lau, Luk [Roll C] (1 of 2) June 1989 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Photos include: S. Lew, Eula Moy, Joe Lam, Qiv, Sybil Wong, Wu, Paul Wing, Shien, Leung-Tokar, Lau, Luk [Roll C] (2 of 2) June 1989 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- ESL Program - Class Photos (1 of 2) June 1989 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- ESL Program - Class Photos (2 of 2) June 1989 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Day Care Center, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Local 23-25 Unite! (Box 11, Folder 20)
- CLUW Activities [Luncheon, Xmas Party, Parade], 1990-1992 (Box 11, Folder 21)
- CLUW Activities [Luncheon, Xmas Party, Parade], 1990-1992 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- CLUW Activities [Luncheon, Xmas Party, Parade], 1990-1992 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Local 23-25 Unite! (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Pre-Retirement Seminar, Unite!, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- CLUW Committee [Caribe Hilton] (Box 11, Folder 26)
- CLUW NYC Awards Luncheon, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 27)
- APA:A, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 28)
- Language Rights Rally. Pre-retirement Seminar. ESL Assembly. Hispanic Labor Committee, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 29)
- GIDC Graduation & Katie Visits CLUW Sisters, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 30)
- Events, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 31)
- Ellis Island & Labor Day Parade: 9/1990 (Box 11, Folder 32)
- Spring Conference, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 33)
- CLUW Convention(s) [Seattle & Pittsburgh]: Nov. 89/Nov. 91, 1989-1991 (Box 11, Folder 34)
- CLUW & ILG Activities, 1986-1989 (Box 11, Folder 35)
- Photos: Miami, FL - June 1992 (Box 11, Folder 36)
- ILG Convention & CLUW Activities, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 37)
- Asian Labor Festival, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 38)
- ILGWU Convention [Fontainebleau Hotel, Miami, FL] - June 1992 (Box 11, Folder 39)
- Photos (1 of 3) - 12/18/1993 (Box 11, Folder 40)
- Photos (2 of 3) - 12/18/1993 (Box 11, Folder 41)
- Photos (3 of 3) 12/18/1993 (Box 11, Folder 42)
- Photos (1 of 3), 1995 (Box 11, Folder 43)
- Photos (2 of 3), 1993 (Box 11, Folder 44)
- Photos (3 of 3), 1995 (Box 11, Folder 45)
- APALA, SS Rally: CLUW Award (1 of 2), 1995 (Box 11, Folder 46)
- APALA, SS Rally: CLUW Award (2 of 2), 1995 (Box 11, Folder 47)
- Pre-Retirement Conference, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 48)
- APALA Board Meeting [Hawaii], 1993 (Box 11, Folder 49)
- Albany Lobby Day - 6/5/1990 (Box 11, Folder 50)
- Images digitized from the collection. (Box 12)